<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bobquest's Technical  Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://bobquest33.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bobquest33.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-11T13:11:51-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://bobquest33.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Priyabrata Dash]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bobquest33@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting mean with mean stack]]></title>
    <link href="http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2014/02/11/getting-mean-with-mean-stack/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-11T09:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2014/02/11/getting-mean-with-mean-stack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a busy week for me where I had been trying to setup a node js development/test environment where I can test
my sample applications and learn node js. This environment will also act as a sandbox for me to learn node, mongo db and
angular js. The whole process of finding a VPS (Amazon AWS), custom Linux image (Bitnami) and an appropriate framework was difficult. The point
in favour of mean stack was the full set of node js libraries that would have helped me in developing a fully functional
website. Along with this using yoeman automation tools I am sure I will be able to automate a large part of the developemnt
process. Next I need to look into my deployment, process management, scheduling, testing and scaling process. In all this the
quest form my perfect application is still on.</p>

<p>Tools/Frameworks used so far:
1. Bitmani Node stack and bitnami cloud hosting (<a href="https://app.bitnamihosting.com/">https://app.bitnamihosting.com/</a>)
2. Mean stack (refer <a href="http://mean.io">http://mean.io</a>)
3. git-deploy (Easy way to deploy any code to sandbox/prod environment)
4. pm2 (A very good cli tool for process management for node js applications <a href="https://github.com/Unitech/pm2">https://github.com/Unitech/pm2</a>)</p>

<p>Still there is a lot of way to go to really making a production ready application.
As part of my app I am planning to integrate a blog as well so that I can track my development journey
through out the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning about startups]]></title>
    <link href="http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2014/01/31/learning-about-startups/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T15:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2014/01/31/learning-about-startups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Behind every success there is a painful experience of successive failures.</p></blockquote>

<hr />

<p>Learned about lean startup process, also concepts about customer centered business development process. And how a clear idea, pivots, one page business plan and an iterative process of customer interaction can bring about a big change in the way we start a business today. My only goal for the next few weeks will be to develop my minimum viable product and getting it online. If you still not make any head or tail of my ideas, then &nbsp;keep waiting for my next posts where I will write my experiences about making a startup.</p>

<p>I firmly believe that with a clear vision, by proper planning and by my resolve to take risks I will be able to succeed in starting my first startup.</p>

<p>So keep waiting for my next posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy New Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/happy-new-year/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T04:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2014/01/02/happy-new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy New year to all the webbies, this year is going to bring more new possibilities and new
expectations from mobile users and gonna bring the speed of high speed computing and make
bit coin the currency of web. As far as I am concerned my knowledge seeking quest will continue.
To learn boundary technologies and be strong in the existing technologies that I know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christmas Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2013/12/24/christmas-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-24T05:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2013/12/24/christmas-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the eve of Christmas I thought of wtriting a script that can find all the best Christmas jokes and receipies available on the web. It will be fun to automate such a script which I can also use in future as well. This will involve writing a script
in Ruby, Mechanize, Nokogiri and finding the matches for our search criteria and showing it to the screen.</p>

<p>As a further work we can also use to save the output to a mongo db and if possible show it as a webpage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My first Octopress Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2013/12/24/my-first-octopress-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-24T04:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bobquest33.github.io/blog/2013/12/24/my-first-octopress-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my quest for better blogging engines and ways of hacking my way through to create a automated blog.
I stumbled upon Octopress. The combination of ruby, jekyll, sinatra  and the beauty of commandline makes
Octopress a nice way to try at blogging for me. The most important aspect for me to use
this blog engine is to use my favorite text editor while typing my blog and running
some cool commandline rake tasks to publish it. Hope I get chance to write more and more
blogs using Octopress.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
